# **Giselle Sanchez**

gisellesanchez@pursuit.org

https://github.com/gsanchez13 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/gsanchez13/ | www.gissanchez.com

#### **SKILLS**

#### Technical

ECMAScript 6, React, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, HTML5, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Postman, Git, GitHub, Data Structures & Algorithms, Redux, Excel, Code Review and Whiteboarding.

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Ethic Attire**

In alignment with the UN's sustainable fashion goals, this full stack web application aims to make an impact in the fashion industry by providing a simple clothing tracking system, education on materials, and resources for future purchases to consumers.

- Worked collaboratively with peers during a week-long Uber sponsored Hackathon event.
- Curated frontend that displays individual clothing items belonging to a user, developed with React libraries, and
  uses vanilla CSS to create a simple and appealing UI for better user experience.
- Created polished PostgreSQL queries for specific data return in routes.

## **Marathoner**

A full stack web social application that allows users to interact with one another based on television shows they are currently watching.

- Uses RESTful API requests with PostgreSQL queries to obtain information about programs.
- Formats client-friendly frontend with React components.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Citi

# Remote / Tampa, FL

# Technology Analyst - Data Services - Finance

July 2021 - Present

Responsibilities include review of Target Record Layout for each retail product under team scope (Deposits, Credit Cards, Personal Loans and Mortgages). Providing product knowledge and support across business and engineering teams. Reviewing and approving business and functional requirements documents for issue remediations. Creating and tracking change requests for data issues. Testing DQ rules with pre/post enriched data to ensure proper functionality. Updating monthly Book of Work presentation with team metrics and assisting in Script Reductions through pseudo logic review and weekly calls to ensure timely decommissions.

# Technology Analyst - Digital Transformation - EO&T

August 2020 - July 2021

Responsibilities included setting up a Proof of Concept for Data Consumption Workbench project, with focus on
pulling data from internal databases directly to BI tools, creating and uploading dashboards for solution testing,
and creating schemas, documentation, and presentations for solutions. BI tools tested included PowerBI, KNIME
and Arcadia, and Snowflake data cloud to support company goal of redesigning the data architecture.

## Technology Intern

**July 2020 – August 2020** 

Participated in a 5-week summer internship that focused on Data Analysis, Data Wrangling and Visualization,
 Cloud Engineering with AWS, UX safety and soundness and Developer best practices.

# **NorthEast Community Bank**

**New York. NY** 

#### **Customer Service Associate**

June 2018 - June 2020

- Managed clientele's finances through extensive record keeping, active customer service and account changes with use of MISER online banking software.
- Used a cross-departmental support system to resolve customer issues and inquiries daily, while also handling
  cash in terms of incoming and outgoing shipments, ATM management, and customer disbursements.
- Maintained a secure system by establishing relationships with patrons through functional communication, strict protocols, and due diligence, considering FDIC and BSA regulations.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Pursuit** 

Long Island City, NY June 2019 - June 2020

12-month Full Stack Web intensive coding program with a 9% acceptance rate.

New York, NY

**Baruch College - Zicklin School of Business** 

Jan 2016 - May 2018

Bachelor of Business Administration in International Business, Minors in Marketing and Spanish